comparethemarket.com 2018-09-07

# Compare the Market - Privacy & Cookie Policy

### Summary

We take our data protection obligations very seriously and it is important to us that you understand how we use your personal data. This Privacy Policy sets out in detail the purposes for which we process your personal data, who we share it with, what rights you have in relation to that data and everything else that we think it is important for you to know.

The main purpose for which we process your personal data is to provide you with services that you request from us through **www.comparethemarket.com** (the Website). We may need some information from you about health or criminal convictions to do this. We cannot display quotes for certain types of insurance (such as life insurance or vehicle insurance) without this data. We will also process personal data for other purposes, such as marketing (where you have consented), market research and fraud prevention. We will only ever keep your personal data for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which we need that personal data.

We will need to share some of your personal data with some third parties, for example our partners and suppliers. Partners who provide quotes to you through our website will make checks against various databases to assess your eligibility for a quote and will make decisions about you by wholly automated means. Those partners are responsible for how they process your personal data. You can view a list of the partners that we work with by clicking **here**.

You have various rights in relation to your personal data which can be exercised by contacting us using the details set out in this Privacy Policy.

### Who is processing your data?

We are Compare the Market Limited and we are the data controller of the personal data that you provide on the Website and/or that we collect about you. This means that we are the company responsible for deciding how your data is processed.

Compare the Market Limited is part of the BGL Group of Companies and provides products and services under various brands. If you want to know more about the BGL Group of Companies and its brands, you can find out more at **[www.bglgroup.co.uk](https://www.bglgroup.co.uk/ "BGL group LTD")**.

**Vehicle, home and pet insurance**

In order to display insurance quotes on the Website, we need to send your personal data to the panel of insurance partners that provide quotes on our website. This is so that they can generate a quote for us to display to you on the Website. When those insurance partners use your personal data to generate a quote, each of them will be acting as a data controller of that personal data. This means that the insurance partners are in charge of how they handle your data and we are not responsible for this. If you provide them with any additional data on their website or if you decide to take out a policy with an insurance partner the use of your data will be subject to that insurance partner's own privacy policy which you should find on their website.

You can see a list of our insurance partners **here**.

**Life, health and income protection Insurance**

Lifesearch Limited:

Our life and critical illness insurance comparison service is provided by our comparison service partner Lifesearch Limited who will also be a data controller in relation to any data you provide in relation to a quote for life insurance.

They will share your personal data with any insurance providers they work with in order to provide your quote.

If you use the talk to us service to talk to Lifesearch then any data that you provide to them directly will be subject to their privacy policy.

Assured Futures Limited

Our over 50's life, health and income protection insurance comparison service is provided by our comparison service partner Assured Futures Limited who will also be a data controller in relation to any data you provide in relation to a quote.

They will share your personal data with any insurance providers they work with in order to provide you a quote.

If you provide your telephone number to confirm that you would like Assured Futures Limited to contact you, Assured Futures will use your data to contact you and provide assistance to you regarding your quote.

You can find further information about Assured Futures including contact information for their Data Protection Officer in Assured Future's privacy policy on their website available at **<https://www.assuredfutures.co.uk/common-page/privacy-policy/>**.

**Travel Insurance**

Our travel insurance comparison service is provided by our comparison service provider Investment Discounts On-Line Limited (Theidol.com) who will also be a data controller in relation to any data you provide in relation to a quote for travel insurance.

They will share your personal data with any insurance providers they work with in order to provide your quote.

Before you click through to a provider we'll ask you if you want to enter your email address so you can claim a reward at a later date. This is optional to provide and will only be used to administer our rewards scheme.

**Breakdown Insurance**

Our breakdown insurance comparison service is provided by our comparison service provider Comparison Creator who will also be a data controller in relation to any data you provide in relation to a quote for breakdown insurance.

They will share your personal data with any insurance providers they work with in order to provide your quote.

**Business insurance**

Our business insurance comparison service is provided by our comparison service provider Simply Business is a trading name of Xbridge Limited who will also be a data controller in relation to any data you provide in relation to a quote for business insurance.

They will share your personal data with any insurance providers they work with in order to provide your quote.

If you use the telephone helpline to call Simply Business they will be the data controller of any data that you provide directly to them which will be subject to their own privacy policy.

**Credit cards**

You do not need to provide us with any personal data to view the details of credit cards displayed on our Website.

If you decide to click through to a credit card provider, any personal data you provide will be subject to the credit card provider's privacy policy and they will be the data controller.

Before you click through to a credit card provider we'll ask you if you want to enter your email address so you can claim a reward at a later date. This is optional to provide and will only be used to administer our rewards scheme.

The credit card comparison service on our Website is provided by Runpath Regulated Services Limited.

**Loans, current accounts, savings accounts and mortgages**

You do not need to provide us with any personal data to view the details of loans, current accounts, savings accounts and mortgages displayed on our Website.

If you decide to click through to any provider, any personal data you provide will be subject to the provider's privacy policy.

**Mortgage broker service**

The mortgage broker service on our Website is run by moneyQuest Mortgage Brokers Limited. If you decide to contact them or request them to contact you they will be the data controller in respect of any personal data that they process about you and this will be subject to their own privacy policy. If you request to be contacted we will pass them your personal data in order to facilitate this.

**Mortgages**

If you use our indicative mortgage eligibility check service, the personal data you provide (including any data about any joint applicant) will be processed by Runpath Regulated Services Limited (RRS). RRS is a data controller alongside Compare the Market Limited in respect of its use of your personal data for this service and you can find out more information on how they may process your data [**here**](https://www.runpath.com/regulated/privacypolicy "https://www.runpath.com/regulated/privacypolicy").

As part of the indicative eligibility checking service RRS will need to retrieve and use data from one or more of the three main Credit Reference Agencies (CRAs) in order to provide your eligibility results.

A Credit Reference Agency (CRA) is a company that collects personal information from various sources and provides that personal information for variety of uses (including to prospective lenders for the purposes of making credit decisions).

RRS will search a CRA who will provide information about you which RRS will use to assess creditworthiness and your likely eligibility for a mortgage . The CRA will provide RRS with the publicly held data, including the electoral roll and shared credit performance data. If you have a financial associate their data may also be provided. This data is not shared with Compare the Market.

When the CRA receives a search from RRS they will place a quotation search footprint on your credit report, regardless of whether you progress any application. This search will not affect your ability to gain credit. This may show in your credit report Compare the Market – Mortgage.

If you choose to pursue an application, any data that you provide to that lender to progress your application will be subject to that lender's own privacy policy.

RRS will only retain data retrieved from CRAs for 90 days.

More information about each CRA and what it does with personal data is available at the following locations:

Call Credit:  
•www.callcredit.co.uk/crain

Equifax:  
•www.equifax.co.uk/crain

Experian:  
•www.experian.co.uk/crain

You can contact any of the CRA's if you wish to obtain a copy of your credit report.

Experian, Consumer Help Service, PO Box 8000, Nottingham NG80 7WF or call 0844 4818000 or log on to **[www.experian.co.uk](https://www.experian.co.uk/ "https://www.experian.co.uk/")**.

CallCredit, Consumer Services Team, PO Box 491, Leeds, LS3 1WZ or call 0870 0601414

Equifax PLC, Credit File Advice Centre, PO Box 1140, Bradford, BD1 5US or call 0844 335 0550 or log on to **[www.myequifax.co.uk](https://www.equifax.co.uk/ "https://www.equifax.co.uk/")**

**Homeowner loan broker service**

The homeowner loan broker service on our website is run by Runpath Regulated Services Limited. If you decide to contact them or request them to contact you they will be the data controller in respect of any personal data that they process about you and this will be subject to their own privacy policy. If you request to be contacted we will pass them your personal data in order to facilitate this.

Before you click through to a loan provider we'll ask you if you want to enter your email address so you can claim a reward at a later date. This is optional to provide and will only be used to administer our rewards scheme.

**Energy**

Energy comparison service

The energy comparison service on our Website is provided by Energy Helpline who are a data controller in respect of any personal data you input for the purposes of using the energy comparison service, including direct debit details which are collected directly by Energy Helpline. When you select to switch providers, Energy Helpline will pass your personal data including your direct debit details to the energy providers to allow them to process your switch. Any use of your personal data when you switch will be subject to the energy provider's privacy policy which we are not responsible for.

If you've signed up for our energy savings service then we will use the data you have provided regarding your postcode, energy supplier and usage details to carry out regular searches of supplier tariffs.

Business energy comparison service

The business energy comparison service on our Website is provided by Energylinx who are a data controller in respect of any personal data you input for the purposes of using the business energy comparison, including direct debit details which are collected directly by Energylinx. When you select to switch providers, Energylinx will pass any personal data including your direct debit details to the energy provider to allow them to process your switch. Any use of your personal data when you switch will be subject to the energy providers privacy policy which we are not responsible for.

**Broadband, phone, TV and mobile**

Our Website also lets you compare broadband, phone, TV and mobile deals. This service is provided by Decision Technologies Limited. You can view deals available and click through to the suppliers without providing us with any personal data. You can choose to enter your postcode in order to view details of deals that are more relevant to you (for example: Decision Technologies Limited can use your postcode to perform an availability check for suppliers in your area).

If you decide to click through to a supplier or telephone a supplier, any personal data you provide will be subject to that supplier's privacy policy. If you place an order with a supplier by telephone, Decision Technologies Limited will collect your telephone number to track the progress of the order you have placed.

Decision Technologies will be a data controller in relation to any personal data they collect when you use the broadband, TV or mobile comparison service, and will be subject to their **[privacy policy](https://broadband.comparethemarket.com/privacypolicy "https://broadband.comparethemarket.com/privacypolicy")**. 

Before you click through to a provider we'll ask you if you want to enter your email address so you can claim a reward later and to send you information about the last deal you have viewed. This is optional to provide and will only be used to administer our rewards scheme and trigger one single email about the last deal you view. If you choose to opt in for marketing or to participate in our rewards scheme, we will be the data controller of that data and we will process it for the purposes set out in this policy.

### Where do we get the data from?

**From you**

Most of the data that we process will be data that we collect from you directly when you request a quote. We will ask you various questions to collect the data we need for the purpose of providing quotes and comparison information. We will not be able to provide a quote unless you answer the mandatory questions. Where questions are optional, we will explain what we need the data for.

**From our insurance partners**

We will also obtain certain personal data about you from the insurance partners on our panel if you take out an insurance policy with them through our Website. This will include information about whether or not you took out a policy with the insurance partner and the type of policy. We use this information to track sales as well as improve our Website, our services and our customer journey. If there are any complaints or queries about your quote or your policy, we and the relevant insurance provider(s) will also exchange information about the complaint or query to ensure it is appropriately investigated and dealt with.

If you make a claim for one of our rewards the insurance partner may also provide us with information including how you purchased your policy and which policy you purchased to help us to verify your claim.

**From our comparison service partners**

We will also obtain some personal data about you from the comparison service partners listed above in relation to the service they provide. For example, they will give us information about what policy or product you purchased and when.

**From your use of the Website and our services**

We also collect data about you based on your actions, for example we collect data about how and when you use the Website, our mobile app or our services so that we can build up a picture of you as a customer. This can include information such as how many quotes you have obtained for insurance, mouse clicks/taps, mouse movements, page scrolling and text entered into forms which we collect through software which monitors how customer use our Website and our app. This helps us to provide you with a good service and to design improvements to our products and services (including changes to our website) but is also used to help us to prevent and detect fraud.

If you use our webchat service we will keep a record of the conversation. We do this so that we have an accurate record of your conversation with us. We also use this data for monitoring and quality control purposes and may use it for training purposes.

We, and our partners collect some of this data by using cookies, web beacons and pixel tags. A cookie is a small file that is placed on your device, which enables a server to identify that device and allows us to offer the best services possible by allowing us to recognise you as a unique user and provide us with information about how you use our website. Cookies are commonly used on the Internet and do not harm your computer system. Web beacons and pixel tags are similar to cookies and allow us to collect information about how you use our website and help us to offer you the best service.

You can read our cookie policy **here** for more information.

We may use web beacons and pixel tags alongside cookies both on our Website and in any emails we sent to you. Information collected may include items such as the IP address of your computer, the time you visited our Website and what links you clicked on or when you opened our emails. We may also use information from cookies or tags when you click through from comparethemarket.com to our partners' websites to help us understand which quotes you have progressed and if you have completed your purchase. Further information about cookies, web beacons and pixel tags can be found at http://www.allaboutcookies.org.

This Website also uses Google Analytics to allow us to monitor how users use our Website. We use services provided by Google to do this including Google's Remarketing and Advertising Reporting Features. The features that we use include Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting and integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data for advertising purposes including the collection of the data via advertising cookies and identifiers. As part of this activity, if you have a Google account and have allowed Google to associate your web and app browsing history so that you may receive personalised ads then Google may collect a Google identifier which allows them to identify your Google account when you are using this Website (including where you use different devices to access this website). Google use this data alongside other data they may collect about you, which may include your location, search history, YouTube history and data from other sites that partner with Google, to provide us with aggregated and anonymised information which assists us in understanding how individuals are using our website. Alongside Google Analytics, this Website uses Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP), this is a service provided by Google which allows webpages to load more quickly on a mobile device by allocating a Client ID to your mobile device if you have loaded the web page before. Please refer to our cookie policy for details of the cookies that are used in relation to Google Analytics activity. If you require further information or wish to opt out of Google Analytics Remarketing and Advertising Reporting Features then please visit  **[Google's currently available opt-outs](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Google's currently available opt-outs")**.

If you contact us electronically, we may collect your electronic identifier e.g. Internet Protocol (IP) address, or device ID or telephone number supplied by your service provider. This information may be used by us and/or shared with and used by our partners to aid in the detection of fraud. Where such data is used by a partner, this will be subject to the partner's own privacy policy.

**Our suppliers**

We will sometimes use third parties to process personal information on our behalf. Our partners may do the same when they are processing your personal information for the purposes of providing a quote for comparison. Where third parties process your personal information on our behalf, we will have a contract in place with them placing obligations on them to keep your data secure and only use it for the purposes that we authorise. The third parties that we use may include, for example, IT service providers and market research agencies.

**Where our insurance partners and comparison service partners collect data from**

In order to provide you with a quote for comparison, our insurance partners and/or comparison service partners will exchange information about you with other companies and/or carry out checks with various databases. These checks are standard practice in the insurance and financial services industries. Each of our insurance partners or comparison service partner is a data controller in respect of these checks and we are not responsible for those checks. We have set out below some of the common databases that they may check.

Checks against existing records

Some of our insurance partners may carry out checks against data they already hold on your (or is held by the company whose brand they administer the product for, or members of their group of companies such as data from existing products, account data or loyalty scheme data. They may use this data to help them assess and rate your application for a quote and determine your premiums. They may also pass this data to their insurance underwriters for these purposes where applicable.

DVLA

Where we ask you for your, or any named driver's, driving licence number, we will pass this to our insurance partners who may pass this to the DVLA in order for a search to be carried out to confirm your (or any named driver's) licence status, entitlement and relevant restriction information and endorsement/conviction data.

Undertaking searches using your driving licence number helps insurers check information to prevent fraud and ensure policy premiums are fair. A search with the DVLA will not show on your (or your named driver's) driving licence record.

For details relating to information held about you by the DVLA, please visit **[www.dvla.gov.uk](https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/driver-and-vehicle-licensing-agency "DVLA.gov")**.

Credit searches

Many of our insurance partners will carry out checks with credit reference agencies when they generate a quote for comparison. These checks may include-

  * checks against publicly available information such as the Electoral Register, County Court Judgments, bankruptcy or repossession information;
  * checks against data relating to your credit history. Credit Reference Agencies share information with other organisations, enabling applications for financial products to be assessed or to assist the tracing of debtors, or to prevent fraud. Our insurance partners may ask Credit Reference Agencies to provide a credit scoring computation. Credit scoring uses a number of factors to work out risks involved in any application. A score is given to each factor and a total score obtained and this together with other factors will be used to assess your application for a quote.

The Credit Reference Agencies will keep a record of the search and you may see this recorded on your credit file. The name of the company that carried out the search will be stated on your credit search and if you have any queries regarding any search that has been carried out you will need to contact the company directly. If you want to check the information that the Credit Reference Agencies hold about you then you can contact them directly. The main credit reference agencies are Call Credit, Experian and Equifax.

Claims and Underwriting Exchange and Other Registers and Databases

Our insurance partners will exchange information with various databases and registers to help them to check information provided, to detect and prevent crime or fraud and to obtain information about your no claims history. These may include the Claims and Underwriting Exchange Register, the Hunter Database, the Motor Insurance Anti-Fraud and Theft Register, the No Claims History Database and any other relevant industry databases or registers. Some insurance providers who offer products designed for students or graduates may also undertake additional checks against higher education sources to verify your student or graduate status.

**Publicly available sources**

We use some open sources of data which are not personal data (such as information about particular geographic areas) and combine this with the personal data that we hold about you (such as your own address). For example, if you request a home insurance quote, we might pre-populate information about your house value from publicly available sources. We will make it clear where we do this and you must check the information to make sure it is correct. This information will be passed to our insurance partners in order to assess insurance risk and provide you with an accurate quote.

**Providing data about other people**

You will sometimes need to provide us with data about other people, for example where you request a quote for a policy which includes another person as a joint policyholder or named driver. You may also obtain quotes on behalf of your family or friends. Where you give us data about someone else, you must make sure that you have made that person aware of this Privacy Policy and that they are happy for you to provide their data. Where this privacy policy refers to "your data" this also includes data about anyone else named on the policy or whose data you provide us with.

### What do we use your data for?

The data that we hold is used for the following purposes:-

**Part 1 - Providing you with our services**

The personal data that we use for the purposes set out in this Part includes: your name, contact details, date of birth, address history, driving history, claims history, any previous convictions, medical history, details about your vehicle and/or your home and belongings, details about your relationship, information about your employment and income, identification information and your no claims history.

_Providing you with a service and administering your account._

We use the data set out above to:

  * provide you with the insurance, utilities and financial products comparison services you request from us (which includes both sharing information with our product providers and our comparison service partners who collect and share your information as set out under "Who is processing your data" above);
  * send you any reminders that you have set up
  * send you any energy saving service information if you have signed up for this service
  * automatically generate quotes when your policies are due for renewal if you have opted into this service (you can opt out of this service at any time by changing the settings in your account)
  * store your documents if you use the "Your Documents" feature, we also carry out analysis of your documents to identify the key information from the documents to make it easier for you to find the information you need;
  * communicate with you about our services, for example send you confirmation emails regarding your quotes or your account details. When you obtain a quote with us, you will automatically be sent confirmation of your quote by email or SMS so that you have a record of your quote and can easily retrieve your quote in the future;
  * manage, run and administer your account if you choose to set up an account with our Website; and
  * help us build up a picture of you as a customer to ensure that we provide you with more relevant information, such as showing you the right content at the right time.

Our partners will use this data to generate a quote to be displayed to you on the Website and they will be data controllers in relation to their use of the data for this purpose. If you would like information about how our partners process data data we recommend that you visit their websites to read their privacy policy. Our comparison service partners will use this data to provide the relevant comparison services as set out under "Who is processing your data" above and they will be data controllers in relation to their use of the data for this purpose. This will only use your personal data for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.

For some products we will give you the option to have two of our insurance partners who provide you with the two lowest prices to contact you to discuss your quote and where you consent, the insurance partners will use your data to contact you regarding your quote.

Data protection law says that we have to tell you the legal basis on which we process your personal data. In relation to personal data used for providing you with a service and managing your account, we process this data because it is necessary to perform the contract that we have in place with you to provide you with our services.

**Part 2 – Fraud Prevention**

Inorder to prevent and detect fraud we and/or our partners and/or comparison service partners may use the personal data set out above at any time to:

  1. Check and/or share your details with fraud prevention and detection agencies; and
  2. Share information about you with other organisations including the police, where necessary and proportionate; and
  3. Carry out analysis on data that is held in order to assist the identification of Fraud.

If false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified, details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies. Law enforcement agencies may access and use this information.

In relation to the personal data processed for fraud prevention, we process this we have a legitimate business interest in carrying out these activities to help minimise the risk of fraud or crime occurring and in its detection.

**Part 3 – Our Reward Schemes**

The personal data that we use for the purposes set out in this Part includes: your name, contact details (including your address), details about any policies you take out with any of our insurance partners or other products you buy through our Website and any other information you provide to us, for example as part of any complaints or queries regarding our reward schemes.

We run certain rewards schemes to reward our customers for buying policies and other products through the Website. Please see **here** for more information about our rewards schemes. We will use the data set out above to validate your eligibility to participate in our reward schemes and to administer the schemes.

We will also use this data to contact you in relation to our reward schemes and to deal with any complaints or queries you have in relation to the rewards schemes. We will exchange data with our partners where necessary for the administration of any rewards schemes. We process this data because we have a legitimate interest in processing the data in order to effectively administer our reward scheme and provide you with the reward scheme you have requested.

Please see the section below headed "Meerkat Movies" for information about how personal data is collected and used by our Meerkat Movies app.

**Part 4 – Other Uses of Data** **  
**

_Marketing_

When you provide your details you will be given an opportunity to confirm whether you are happy to receive marketing material from us. If you confirm you are happy to receive this material, we will use your postal address, email address and telephone number to send you marketing materials by post, email, telephone call or SMS. We do not pass your data to other companies for marketing purposes.

If you consent to us contacting you for marketing purposes, we will disclose an anonymised version of your email address (we use a process called hashing to protect your details) to third party social media sites such as Facebook to enable us to display marketing to you via such sites. "Hashing" is similar to encryption and means that we scramble the plain text of your email address to create a unique and irreversible message. This means that the social media sites do not receive a plain text version of your email address. Where we do this, we require social media providers only to use your information for the purposes of enabling us to display marketing to you through their site and not for any of their own purposes.

You can change your mind at any time by logging into your account and updating your preferences. You can also unsubscribe from emails by clicking on the unsubscribe link on any marketing emails that we send you, updating your preferences in your account or by unsubscribing on our [**website**](https://preferences.comparethemarket.com/ "Contact preference centre").

This will not impact any communications that we need to send you for the purpose of your quote, for example confirmation of your quote or your account details, notifications we need to send you regarding any rewards you have claimed or communications necessary for any other services you have requested that we provide to you.

Your personal data will also be used to assist us and our approved advertising providers with our advertising activities, as set out in more detail in the "Targeting Cookies" section of our **Cookies Policy**. Targeting cookies do not collect information that is directly identifiable to you, such as your name, email address and information you enter into forms on our website. They collect information about your browsing activity and your device to enable our providers to serve our advertising to you. Most of these cookies are set by our providers who will be responsible for how the cookies (and information collected by them) are used.

However, we do use the personal data that we hold about you to put you into "segments" based on your interests and needs so that we can ensure the advertising you see is relevant to you. To do this effectively, we need to share some of your information with some of our providers so that they can combine it with the information collected by their cookies and serve advertising to audiences that we select. The information shared is limited to your email address, IP address, information about which products you may be interested in such as which pages of our website or app you have visited or which of our emails you have clicked on and whether you have purchased a policy or claimed a reward with us. Information is always shared in an encrypted, non-identifiable form. Where we do this, we will be jointly responsible with the relevant provider for how that personal data is used. More information about our providers and the cookies used, including how to opt out, is set out in our **Cookies Policy**.

_Market Research_

From time to time we may want to use your postal address, email address and/or telephone number to contact you to assist us with our research by asking you a few questions about the service you have received or by asking if you would like to complete a review of our services. We may sometimes ask market research companies to contact you on our behalf.

If you would prefer us not to contact you for market research purposes then you can let us know by contacting us at **[data.request@comparethemarket.com](mailto:data.request@comparethemarket.com)** or by updating your preferences in your account.

_Research and Analysis Activities_

We and our partners use data relating to your quotes, including the personal data you input to request your quotes and information about the policies or contracts you have taken out, to carry out various research and analysis activities to help us to regularly review and improve the products and services we or our partners provide and carry out research. We also share this data with our insurance providers and comparison service providers to enable them to use this data for these purposes. Where possible, data will be shared on an anonymised basis. The data will not be used to make any decisions that will affect you or any other individual and we require our partners and comparison service providers to delete the data as soon as the relevant research and analysis activity is concluded.

We also use the data that we collect about you through your Website usage to carry out research and analysis into usage and activities on our Website to enable us to continue to improve our Website and our products and services.

In relation to personal data used for the purposes described in this Part 4, we process this data because we have a legitimate business interest in carrying out these activities to promote and improve our business. We have ensured appropriate safeguards to protect your rights when processing this data for these purposes.

**Part 5 – Special Categories of Personal Data and Criminal Convictions**

In order to provide your quotes we may ask you to provide data which data protection law classifies as "special personal data". This includes information about your health (such as any medical conditions). We may also need you to provide information relating to criminal convictions or alleged or actual criminal offences, for example traffic offences, in order to provide your quotes. We will also need to share this data with our insurance partners to enable them to generate their quotes for you.

Where we collect special personal data and criminal conviction or offence data for the purposes above, we process this data because it is in the substantial public interest to do so for the purposes of arranging and/or advising on contracts of insurance.

It may also be necessary for us to retain a copy of any special personal data and criminal conviction or offence data for the purpose of making or defending claims or preventing or detecting crime, including fraud.

### Our Rewards schemes

The personal data that we use for the purposes set out in this Part includes: your name, contact details (including your address), details about any policies you take out with any of our insurance partners or other products you buy through our Website and any other information you provide to us, for example as part of any complaints or queries regarding our reward schemes.

We run certain rewards schemes to reward our customers for buying policies and other products through the Website. Please see **here** for more information about our rewards schemes.

We process this data because we have a legitimate interest in processing the data in order to effectively administer our reward scheme provide you with the reward scheme you have requested.

Please see the section below headed "Meerkat Movies and Meerkat Meals" for information about how personal data is collected and used by our Meerkat app.

### Meerkat Movies and Meerkat Meals

If you have activated a Meerkat Movies or Meerkat Meals membership (referred to in this section as “Rewards” and downloaded the Meerkat app (the App), we will use the App to collect and process certain personal data as set out in this section. 

#### **_What personal data do we use?_**

We collect and use the following information through the App:

  * your name, email address and password. This information is collected when you set up an account with comparethemarket.com and is used to log you into the App;
  * information about your location, where you have agreed on the App that we can do so (you can change your mind about this at any time using your device's settings). This involves obtaining location data from your device;
  * information about your use of the App, such as whether you have used your 2 for 1 codes, what movie trailers you have watched on the App, and which restaurants or movies you have searched for; and information about your device, such as your IP address, device profile and device settings (for example, whether you have switched push messaging on or off in your device settings).
  * We will use the data set out above to validate your eligibility to participate in our reward schemes and to administer the schemes. We will also use this data to contact you in relation to our reward schemes and to deal with any complaints or queries you have in relation to the rewards schemes. We will exchange data with our partners where necessary for the administration of any rewards schemes. We will also receive some data from the app about how you have use the reward scheme, for example if you use Meerkat Meals, we will receive information about your use your reward such as when and where you have used your reward and the number of people you used the reward for. This allows us to monitor how customers are using the rewards and to help us make any changes/improvements to our rewards schemes.

#### **_How do we use your personal data?_**

We use your personal data in the following ways and for the following purposes:

  * Your name, email and password are used to log you into the App and to link you to your comparethemarket.com account to check your eligibility for Rewards and that your membership is valid and has not expired.
  * Your name is also used to personalise any messages that we send to you through the App.
  * If you have agreed to receive messages from us, we will either use your device information to send you push messages (where you have opted in specifically to receiving push messages), or we will send in-app messages to you, for example to ask you to review the App.
  * If you have agreed to receive marketing from us we will use your device information to notify you of information, products or services that we think may be of interest to you based on your previous use of the App, such as the release of a new film or a change in the participating restaurants for Meerkat Meals.
  * We will use information about your account to send you service messages relating to your account, for example to let you know if your Rewards are about to expire.

When you first log into the App, you will be asked if you are happy to allow location services. This means that we are sent information by your device about your location. You can turn this setting on and off any time using your device's settings. If you have consented to the use of location services, we will use your location to show you information about which restaurants or cinemas are nearby. We will also use this information to identify when you enter a particular location. For example, we will use this location information to identify when you enter a cinema or restaurant.  We’ll use this information to give us insight as to how you use your Rewards and may also use this information to send you more tailored messages for example reminding you to use your voucher code.

### How long do we keep data?

We'll only keep your personal data as long as we need it and ensure it is securely destroyed when it is no longer required. We do however need to keep certain data after we have provided you with your quotes for certain periods as detailed below.

Generally, you can expect us to keep your data for a period of 5 years from when you obtain your quote. If you have an account with us we will keep your data while your account with us is active and then if you stop using your account we will generally retain your data for a period of 5 years from that point (unless there is a requirement for us to keep the data for longer, for example if there are any ongoing queries or claims relating to your quotes).

We keep data for these periods as it plays an important part in allowing us to undertake fraud detection and prevention activities, allows us to deal with any queries or complaints that may arise regarding quotes that have been provided and allow us to carry out research and analysis to help us improve our products and services (as described in the section headed "What do we use your data for?" above).

Any of our partners who process your data to provide a quote should only keep the data for as long as is necessary in relation to the quote they have provided. If you take out a policy with one of our insurance partners, that partner will keep your personal data in line with its own retention periods and you should check that insurance partner's Privacy Policy for further information.

If you use the 'Your Documents' facility we will keep your documents for a period of 5 years from the date you last used the account as described above.

### Overseas Transfer of Data

We use third party suppliers to process limited personal data about you. Some of these suppliers may be located in countries outside the UK which may not have equivalent laws in place to protect your personal data. For example, we use third party software suppliers such as Microsoft to process data such as your IP address and email address, which Microsoft stores in the USA.

Whenever we do use third party suppliers to process personal data about you outside the UK, we will ensure that your personal data is kept securely, is only used for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy and is afforded equivalent protection as it would be if it were processed in the UK. We do this through various mechanisms, for example making sure that European Commission approved contractual clauses are in place with the supplier or ensuring that suppliers who process personal data in the USA are signed up to the Privacy Shield arrangement. If you are concerned about our use of third party suppliers to process personal data outside the UK, or if you would like any further information about any of these suppliers, please contact us using the details set out under "Contacting us" below.

Our insurance providers and comparison service providers may also process personal data in countries outside the UK which may not have equivalent laws in place to protect your personal data. Our insurance partners and comparison service partners are the data controllers in respect of any such processing and such processing will be subject to their own Privacy Policies.  We do not have any control over whether our partners or comparison service partners process personal data outside the UK but if this do this they must do it in accordance with data protection legislation.

### Your Rights

Data protection law gives you various rights in relation to your personal data. All the rights set out below can be exercised by contacting us using the contact details set out under the "Contacting us" section below. Please note that we can only deal with requests to exercise these rights where they relate to personal data that we process as data controller. If you send us a request which relates to personal data processed by one or more of our partners or comparison service providers as data controllers, we will direct you to the appropriate insurance partner(s) or comparison service provider(s).

Your rights include:-

  * You have the right to ask us to provide a copy of the personal data that we hold about you. This is called a Data Subject Access Request or "DSAR". You can access information about your quotes by logging into your account. If you want to receive other personal data that we hold then you can make a DSAR. When contacting us please describe the information you require and make sure that you tell us any email addresses you or anyone else have used to obtain quotes with us as this allows us to trace all relevant information. Please also include the following: your full name, your date of birth and your full address. For security purposes we can only deal with requests where the contact details you provide match the details we have on file and we may need to ask you for further information to verify your identity. If you have changed your contact details or you require information sending to different contact details please include a copy of your passport or driving licence and proof of address such as a recent utility bill to assist us in verifying your identity. We might also need to ask you for additional information to help us locate the data that you are looking for. Once we have all the information that we need to process your DSAR, we will respond within one month unless your DSAR is very large or complex, in which case we may need to extend this period. If we need to do this we will let you know. If you want to make a DSAR in relation to personal data that is held by any of our insurance partners then you will need to contact them directly. You can find our list of insurance partners **here**.

  * You have the right to ask us to correct inaccurate personal data that we hold about you. If you think any of your personal data is inaccurate, please contact us and, provided we can verify your identity and are satisfied as to the accuracy of the correction requested, we will correct the relevant personal data as soon as we can. You can also amend inaccurate data in your account.

  * You have the right to request that we provide a copy of your personal data in a machine readable format or to ask us to send your personal data to another company. This applies to personal data that you have provided to us, which we have processed electronically, such as personal data you entered on our website when you obtained a quote.

  * You also have the right to ask us to delete personal data that we hold about you. We are obliged to delete personal data in some circumstances, such as where it is no longer needed. However, data protection laws allow us to keep the personal data if we need to, for example if the data is needed for fraud prevention.  In any case, we will retain your personal data in line with the retention periods detailed under "How long do we keep data?" above.    If you use the “Your Documents” facility to store your documents, you can delete the documents at any time by selecting the delete option available in the Your Documents section.

  * You have the right to ask us not to do anything with your personal data except store it in limited circumstances, such as if you and we do not agree on the accuracy of personal data and steps are required to validate it.

  * You have the right to object to us processing certain personal data about you. However, where we need to continue to process the personal data, for example for fraud prevention purposes, we are not obliged to stop processing it.

  * You have the right to ask for significant decisions that have been made about you wholly by automated means to be reviewed. We do not make any significant decisions about you wholly by automated means. However, the nature of the quotes provided by our insurance partners means that they have to use this kind of automated decision making to assess your quotes. If you want any wholly automated decisions in relation to your quotes to be reviewed, you will need to contact the partner who has produced the relevant quote.

### Contacting us

If you would like to contact us about one of your data rights set out under "Your Rights" above, then please contact **[data.request@comparethemarket.com](mailto:data.request@comparethemarket.com)** or write to Data Requests – Saxon House, Bakewell Road, Orton Southgate, PE2 6YS.

If you would like to contact any of our comparison service providers about data that they hold then please contact or visit:-

Lifesearch - **[customercare@lifesearch.co.uk](mailto:customercare@lifesearch.co.uk)**

Assured Futures - **<https://www.assuredfutures.co.uk/common-page/privacy-policy/>**  

energyhelpline - **[data@energyhelpline.com](mailto:data@energyhelpline.com)**

Energylinx - **[DataProtection@energylinxforbusiness.com](mailto:DataProtection@energylinxforbusiness.com)**

The Idol - **[datacontroller@theidol.com](mailto:datacontroller@theidol.com)**

Comparison Creator – **[dataprotection@comparisoncreator.com](mailto:dataprotection@comparisoncreator.com)  
**

moneyQuest - **[info@moneyquest.co.uk](mailto:info@moneyquest.co.uk)**

Decision Technologies – **[dpo@decision.tech](mailto:dpo@decision.tech)**

Simply Business -   **[dataprotectionteam@simplybusiness.co.u](mailto:dataprotectionteam@simplybusiness.co.uk " dataprotectionteam@simplybusiness.co.uk")** **[k](mailto:dataprotectionteam@simplybusiness.co.uk " dataprotectionteam@simplybusiness.co.uk")**

If you would like contact any insurance partner about the data that they hold then please visit that insurance partner’s website and view their privacy policy for details of how to contact them about data matters. A full list of our partners can be found **here**.

If you have any other queries or concerns about this Privacy Policy, or if you would like to contact our Data Protection Officer, you can email **[ctm.dpo@bglgroup.co.uk](mailto:ctm.dpo@bglgroup.co.uk)**  or write to the Data Protection Officer at Compare the Market Limited, Pegasus House, Bakewell Road, Orton Southgate, Peterborough, PE2 6YS.

When contacting us please describe the information you require and make sure that you tell us any email addresses you or anyone else have used to obtain quotes with us as this allows us to trace all relevant information. Please also include the following: your full name, your date of birth and your full address.

### Information Commissioner’s Office

If you have a complaint regarding how your personal data has been processed by us then please contact us first using the complaints procedure set out **[here](https://help.comparethemarket.com/ "Contact us")**.  You also have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office, which regulates data protection compliance. You can find more information by visiting their website www.ico.org.uk.
